TIAGO RODRIGUES DE ALMEIDA

Doctoral Student \diamond ORCID: 0000-0001-9059-6175

(+351) \diamond tmr.almeida96@gmail.pt

29 May, 1996 \$ Portugal

ABOUT ME

I am a doctoral student in Computer Science who has been motivated by Artificial Intelligence since his Master's Degree. After that, I have been developing some very important hard skills to deploy applications in those fields, such as Machine Learning, spanning from the study of Probabilities Theory to practical frameworks (e.g. PyTorch). Besides the complexity and outstanding results that has shown, characteristics that I appreciate, Machine Learning has the capability to change the current world paradigm and I want to be part of this. Nowadays, I am working specifically in Human Behavioural prediction, namely human motion. Besides work, I love travelling because it involves different cultures. Also, when there is enough spare time, I like to develop and deploy homemade projects related to the area that is my main focus — Machine Learning.

EDUCATION

University of Örebro, Sweden

Sep 2020 - Present

Doctoral Student in Computer Science

WASP - Wallenberg AI, Autonomous Systems and Software Program

University of Aveiro, Portugal

Sep 2014 - July 2019

Master in Mechanical Engineering - GPA: 16/20

SPECIALIZATIONS

Amazon Web Services

Nov 2022 -

AWS Technical Essentials

WASP PhD courses

Oct 2020 -

Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning

Matchematics and Machine Learning

Deep Learning and GANs

Learning Feature Representations

CS50 from Harvard University

Jun 2020

CS50x

NVIDIA Mar 2020

Getting started with Deepstream for video analytics on Jetson Nano

Coursera Dec 2019 - Feb 2020

Deep Learning Specialization

TensorFlow in Practice Specialization

Applied Machine Learning in Python Course

Applied Plotting, Charting & Data Representation in Python

Introduction to Data Science in Python

Wall Street English, Aveiro, Portugal

Sep 2017 - Sep 2019

First Certificate in English - B2

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Aveiro, Portugal

Sep 2019 - Aug 2020

Research Fellow

T.6.3.3 - Development of a flexible and low-cost localization and navigation system for PPS6 of the Produtech II SIF 24541 project.

Avesteel, Aveiro, Portugal

Aug 2016

Mechanical Locksmith Assistant

Temporary job in Renault Cacia to improve some pratical hard skills. My task was to dismantle and clean engines from machines.

INTERNSHIPS

Amazon, Barcelona, Spain

Oct 2022 - Apr 2023

Applied Scientist

Transit time estimation from anywhere to anywhere in the EU road transportation network:

- Geospatial data
- Deep Learning for tabular data
- Feature Engineering
- AWS deployment (model at beta stage)

Renault Cacia, Aveiro, Portugal

Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

Electronic Engineer

Implementation of an artificial vision station on a production line to control the components quality. The software used was Sherlock.

PUBLICATIONS

Almeida, T., Santos, V., Mozos, O.M. et al. Comparative Analysis of Deep Neural Networks for the Detection and Decoding of Data Matrix Landmarks in Cluttered Indoor Environments. J Intell Robot Syst 103, 13 (2021). https://doi.org/10.1007/s10846-021-01442-x

Almeida T., Lourenço B., Santos V., "Road detection based on simultaneous deep learning approaches", In: Robotics and Autonomous Systems. 2020, doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.robot.2020.103605, ISSN: 0921-8890

PROJECTS

Multi-Camera and Multi-Algorithm Architecture for Visual Perception onboard the AT-LASCAR2

Master's Thesis (Advisor: Prof. Vítor Santos) - Score 19/20

Blog: https://tmralmeida.github.io/projects/index.html

Youtube channel: https://www.youtube.com/@tmralmeida96/videos

Github: https://github.com/tmralmeida

RELEVANT TECHNICAL SKILLS

LanguagesPortuguese, EnglishProgramming LanguagesPython, C, Matlab

Libraries / Frameworks PyTorch, Pandas, SciPy, Numpy, ROS

Tooling Latex, VSCode, Git, AWS OS Linux, Mac OS, Windows